# Josh Becker

#### **Art Director / Graphic Designer**

Santa Cruz, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Josh-Becker/4a641c456b1e362b

I have 18 years of experience in editorial and advertising design, during which time I served as the art director of five print publications. I've overseen and executed the redesign of entire newspapers and magazines, and have developed others from scratch. I'm also experienced in visual branding, logo development, business collateral, product and label designs, book design, and more.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Creative Director**

Santa Cruz Waves - Santa Cruz, CA - June 2015 to Present

Santa Cruz Waves is a bimonthly surf lifestyle magazine with a circulation of 20,000+. As Creative Director, I ideate and execute all editorial design and layouts (~80 pages per issue), create info-graphics and illustrations, prepare files for and upload files to press, color correct photos, collaborate with the editorial and advertising departments, prepare the magazine for web publishing, and much more.

### Art Director, Graphic Designer

Freelance - Santa Cruz, CA - October 2014 to Present

Art Director of Los Gatos Magazine from 4/2016 to 4/2017.

I redesigned the bimonthly glossy, designed each issue's editorial content, and developed/designed a new sister publication,

The Good Life Collection.

- Designed a hardcover, national-release book (Cannabis Saved My Life, published in 2016 by Whitman Publishing)
- Worked for a large international ad agency designing

business/collateral materials

- Conceptualized and executed logo and visual branding for companies including a food start-up and a high-end furniture brand
- Served as a project-based art director for one-off and new print publications, including Regional Small Business Magazine and Monterey Waves

#### **Art Director, Production Manager**

Good Times Weekly - Santa Cruz, CA - July 1999 to October 2014

Santa Cruz, CA

rslack1515@gmail.com, (831) 234-7526

Art Director, Production Manager / Good Times • Greg Archer, former editor in chief, Good Times, Good Times Weekly is the largest publication in Santa Cruz County, greg@gregarcher.com, (415) 412-2087 Calif. While there, I managed the production and design departments, • Eli Roe, Designer/Co-worker, overseeing a team of designers in our weekly execution of the 140- eli@roestudio.com, (310) 770-8606 page newspaper and an annual budget. I created more than 700

cover designs, which included concept development, illustration and typography. I developed, designed, and published more than a dozen

stand-alone annual publications.

## **EDUCATION**

## Design

San Jose State University 1997

## A.S. in Fire Protection Technology in Fire Protection

Cabrillo College - Santa Cruz, CA January 1993 to May 1996

#### **SKILLS**

Art Direction (10+ years), Creative Suite (10+ years), Logo Design (5 years), Indesign (5 years), Quarkxpress (10+ years), Typography (10+ years), Illustrator (10+ years), Cover Design (10+ years), Creative Direction (2 years), Editorial Design (10+ years)

#### LINKS

http://www.designandart365.com